nickelodeonafrica.com 2018-10-18

# Nickelodeon | Privacy Policy

* **What Is A Privacy Policy?**

Our privacy policy is just our way of telling you how we (or any of our successors and/or associated companies) will collect, store and use any information, which you provide to us, such as your name, age, address, and telephone number or anything else. It also tells you the choices you can make about how the information you provide to us is collected and used. It is important you read through this policy and be sure to get your parent(s)/guardian(s) to read and discuss it with you.

And don't forget, you should always make sure you get the consent of your parent(s)/guardian(s) before giving any information or sending any materials to anyone, including us, whether online, by post or in any other way.

" **We** ", " **us** " and " **our** " means MTV Networks Africa (Pty) Ltd t/a Viacom International Media Networks Africa of 1 Saxon Road, Hyde Park, Johannesburg, 2196. If you have any questions or concerns please contact us. Our contact details can be found [HERE](http://www.nickelodeonafrica.com/info/contacts).

* **The Legal And Important Bit**

We promise to look after and control any information you send us, whether it's personal information (such as your name, address, date of birth or contact details) or other non-personal information (such as your nickname, your computer's address known as an IP address, views or comments).

So whether you register your details on our websites, enter competitions, contact us by phone or email, send us SMS messages, voting for your favourite things online, send us a letter in the post or provide us with your information any other way, this policy will apply, unless we tell you otherwise.

By accepting this Privacy Policy and by providing us with your information, you (and your parent(s)/guardian(s)) agree to the terms of this policy. If you (or your parent(s)/guardian(s)) do not agree with this policy, please do not supply any information.

* **Interacting With Us**

You can interact with us in a number of ways but if you want to interact with us online through our websites, it is always a good idea for you and your parent(s)/guardian(s) to spend time online together for your safety and it may even be fun!

* **Parent(s)'/Guardian(s)' Consent and Checks**

If you are under 18, you will ALWAYS need to get your parent(s)/guardian(s) permission before contacting and interacting with us - whether it's entering one of our competitions, sending us a letter or accessing our websites, especially if you are providing us with personal information.

We may need to check that your parent(s)/guardian(s) are happy for you to provide your information to us. Where we do need to check with your parent(s)/guardian(s), we will ask you for your parent's/guardian's contact details (usually an email address or telephone number) so we can then contact them. 

We will always ask for your parent(s)'/guardian(s)' permission where we want to use your personal information for marketing or research purposes; to send you our newsletter (if we have one to send) or whether you are allowed to receive the prize and can comply with the [GENERAL COMPETITION RULES](http://www.nickelodeonafrica.com/info/general-competition-rules), if you're lucky enough to be selected as a winner of a competition.

We may also carry out checks to ensure that the contact details you have provided for your parent(s)/guardian(s) are your actual parent(s)/guardian(s). So no cheating!

* **What Happens If We Don’t Receive Your Parent(s)'/Guardian(s)' Consent?**

If we:

  1. find out you've cheated;  

  2. discover you've given us fake details for your parent(s)/guardian(s) - very naughty!!; or  

  3. we don’t get a reply from your parent(s)/guardian(s) within a reasonable time (being approximately 5 weeks if you've asked to receive any newsletter we may distribute - for competitions, this time period will be a lot shorter, sometimes maybe only 24 hours);

We will not be able to use your information and will remove your information from our database within a reasonable time.

This may affect the way you may interact with us so, for example, you won't be allowed to enter a competition; your use of our websites may be limited; or you will not be able to receive any marketing materials.

* **Why Do We Need Your Information?**

A lot of the information we ask you to provide is to make sure you can enjoy all the benefits of our websites or so we can tell you if you're lucky enough to win one of our competitions.

You can, of course, ask us to remove your information at any time by contacting us. Our contact details can be found [HERE](http://www.nickelodeonafrica.com/info/contacts).

* **What Else Do We Do With Your Information?**

The information you provide may be used for marketing and research; to provide and personalise our service for you; and to send you newsletters and other information about us and our related products and services (marketing materials) where we have them.

If you'd like to receive marketing materials from us such as our newsletter, you can contact us at any of the contact details found [HERE](http://www.nickelodeonafrica.com/info/contacts), and ask to receive available marketing materials from us.

It is your choice whether you'd like to receive these marketing materials or not and you can change your mind at any time by contacting us.

In order to ensure that any marketing materials, which we may provide to you are likely to be of interest, we may also use information collected about you from cookies (as described below), surveys, household data and any correspondence between you and us, as well as information you provide when you register your details on our websites.

Where we use your personal information for such marketing materials, we will ask your parent(s)'/guardian(s)' permission first BUT where we don’t use your personal information and just uses your non-personal information, we will not ask your parent(s)/guardian(s) for their permission.

* **Who Else May Have Access To Your Information?**

Sometimes we need third parties to carry out a service for us. For example if you win a competition, we may need to pass your information to a third party to arrange delivery of your prize or need advice from any auditor or legal adviser. We will make sure that these third parties keep your information secure; only keep the information for so long as is necessary; and will comply with all South African legislation. 

Apart from the above, we will only pass on your information to third parties if:

  * We have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary for legal proceedings;

  * the information is generic and doesn't identify you, such as whether you're a boy or girl and how you watch our programmes. We may use such information (in whole or in part) to identify trends and may pass this to third parties such as advertisers and business partners to give them a better understanding of our business.

* **International Use Of Your Information**

As we, and our associated companies, operate throughout the world, it may be necessary to transfer your information outside of South Africa. If we need to do this, we promise that any of our associated companies will comply with applicable laws in respect of data protection and will comply with the terms of this policy. Please be advised that your personal information may be transferred to and processed by our affiliates in the United States.  These affiliates comply with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor.  Please see the Safe Harbor Privacy Policy <http://www.viacom.com/privacypolicy/Documents/VIACOM-610657-v1-Safe_Harbor_Policy.pdf> for detailed information on these affiliates' privacy practices. 

* **Cookies and IP Addresses - What Are They?**

Cookies are small files of data that are downloaded onto your computer when you visit a website. They allow websites, such as our websites, to remember your activities on that website and the number of times you have visited. We collect information through this technology to make our website more interesting and useful to you. For instance, when you come to one of our websites via your computer, we collect your IP address. At times, we also use your IP address to collect information about how often you visit our websites.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser settings. Each browser is different, so you may want your parent(s)/guardian(s) to help you and you'll probably need to take a look at your Help menu. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your web experience smoother and some of our services may not work properly.

You may also get cookies from our advertisers. We don’t control these cookies, and once you have clicked on the advertisement and left our website, this policy no longer applies.

* **Links To Other Websites**

When you're on one of our websites, you may be directed to other sites where your information may be collected and this will be outside our control. For example, if you click on a banner advertisement on one of our websites, it may take you from our website to a third party's website. We can’t be responsible for or control the content on another party's website and don't forget that once you've left our website, if you provide any information to the third party, you will need to check their privacy policy as this policy only applies to our websites.

It is important that you stay safe online and if you'd like more information about this then please talk to your parent(s)/guardian(s).

* **Changes To This Policy**

We may change this policy from time to time and will post the latest version on our websites. If we wish to use your information in a way which is incompatible with the information in this policy, we will contact you (and your parent(s)/guardian(s)) to get your consent.   

* **Who Can You Contact?**

If you and/or your parent(s)/guardian(s) want to discuss with us how your information is used; wish us to remove your information from our records; or would like to update your information then please contact us. Our contact details can be found [HERE](http://www.nickelodeonafrica.com/info/contacts).

* **How To Remove Or Amend Your Information**

In addition to contacting us as above, if you have registered your information online on our websites, you can change, update or remove it at any time just by clicking on the relevant link as displayed on the relevant website and following the directions given. If there isn’t a link that allows you to do this, you will need to contact us. Our contact details can be found [HERE](http://www.nickelodeonafrica.com/info/contacts).

You may also be able to stop receiving our newsletters or other marketing materials by clicking on the ‘unsubscribe' link in the emails we send you.

* **More Legal Information**

  1. We will not be liable to you and/or your parent(s)/guardian(s) for any loss or damage however it was caused (including without limitation in contract, tort or statutory duty) in connection with this privacy policy and/or the collection and use of your information by us, other than death or personal injury caused by our (and/or our employees) negligence.
  2. We will comply with the requirements of any data protection laws which may come into effect from time to time.
  3. This policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of South Africa and if there are any disputes the courts of South Africa shall have exclusive jurisdiction.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on **1 September 2015**.
